María Alejandra Pérez

UX / UI Designer

UX / UI Designer with a background in operations and customer support. My experience has taught me how to communicate with stakeholders, provide timely solutions for support incidences, and design processes that understand the customer's struggles and motivations. All of these lessons have really motivated me and inspired me to develop myself in UX/UI design.

Contact information

- mapb1989@gmail.com
- +34677709274
- Barcelona, Spain
- in @mapb1989
- mariaalejandraperez.com

Skills

Technologies & Tools:

Figma | Sketch | Adobe XD | Invision | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin | Miro | Notion

Soft skills

Problem solving |
Adaptability | Time
management | Empathy |
Listening

Hard skills

Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Proficient

German: Beginner

Catalan: Beginner

Work Experience

10/2020 – present **UX/UI Designer (Freelance project)**

FixFirst (Berlin, Germany) [Remote]

SaaS provider for service partners and technicians of home appliances

- Collect requirements and feedback from clients to improve user flow and information architecture of application and desktop dashboard.
- Build components library for UI Designs.
- Create Mockups designs of new mobile application for technicians.
- Redesign existing mockups of desktop dashboard for service partners and technicias website.
- Run demos and usability tests to find points of improvement in the designed products.

05/2018 – 04/2020 Lead Customer Support and operations Engineer

Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

Software provider of Smart WiFi and proximity marketing

- Manage support team.
- Analyze, improve and maintain the company's operational processes.
- Report, replicate and track bugs in the production environment.
- Provide training and support to customers as required.
- Manage customers' projects from contract signature to end of installation.

Projects

05-06/2020 App for streaming services recommendations

UX/UI Final Project at Ironhack (UX Research, IA, Interaction design, UI Design.)
Goal: Offer accurate recommendations for movies and shows streaming services.

Other projects can be found at mariaalejandraperez.com

Education

12/2019 – 06/2020 **UX/UI Designer**

Ironhack (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2014 - 02/2017 Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2007 – 12/2012 **Electronic Engineer**

Universidad Simón Bolívar (Caracas, Venezuela)